This with rules of play for journalists ...
We have heard with Caspar Opitz, our new media ombudsman.
As a media ombudsman, I make sure that TV, radio, newspapers take care of Sig-
-And behaves schyst.
The rules of the game for press, radio and television are to-
-To the media to behave correctly, manage news correctly-
-time seek to describe the truth, be fair-
-Let everyone come to speak, be careful with human-
-What do not want to join in and behave correctly and schist.
If someone writes something stupid about you report it to me.
You do not have court and do with lawyers-
-Out you can report it to me, I look at it and help you.
In a self -cleaning system, the media takes care of it.
Newspapers, TV and radio say: "If we do anything wrong, we handle it."
"We don't need any politicians or courts, but we take care of it."
My role in our system is to keep the legislator away-
-No the media.
It is important for democracy.
Okay, but some don't look up what they post.
Not everyone follows mediaetic rules.
Some call themselves journalists without responsible publishers.
There are gossip sites that want to report rumors.
Just.
But with this one cannot decide what is right or not-
-Os the truth can show up anywhere.
Gossip sites may be right and established media can be wrong-
-and they came out every day, week or month.
But now we read more online and it is a more even flow.
But in the past, those who were distributed every day were called daily newspapers.
Just.
Then they divided them into the morning and evening newspapers-
-Or which part of the day they covered.
Not everyone has a look at that.
Evening newspapers ... come out in the evening, right?
And morning in the morning.
Or?
There may be a little different news.
I do not know.
Evening newspapers in the evening, morning in the morning?
I think morning newspapers may be from the day before, kind of.
And evening newspaper comes from the day, or something.
Now the difference is perhaps mostly a style issue.
Evening newspapers are a bit more sniffy-
-While daily newspapers are a bit more fine cultural and do not take the gossip.
Think some.
But evening newspapers do good excavation journalism-
-and real blood dog digs and digs out injustice.
Examples of evening newspapers: Expressen, Aftonbladet.
Then we have the morning newspapers, and they, think a part-
-Have considered himself having finer ideals and be a little finer.
Examples of morning newspapers: Svenska Dagbladet, Dagens Nyheter.
Then we have local magazines.
There, for example, we have the Barometer in Småland or Västerbottencuriren.
There it can get cranky, when people expect national news-
Just.
It is meant that local magazines-
-Do cover the little life in the local community.
Then local magazines are very good at the local angle.
Do you remember the Skellefteå scarf guy?
In the middle of the crowd he stood, among thousands of other-
-With helmet, outstretched arms, and then that red scarf.
In Sweden, on top of all that-
-The we have SVT and Sweden's Radio with national news and local editors.
And so all magazines that can be about all-
-To journalists when they want to tell about something good that has happened.
There are two of the places.
Then I usually dig a little-
-In the archives of the authorities among paper and decisions taken by politicians.
I think that is a way to find things that are exciting.
He seemed to be sway.
But he said that journalists are not always popular.
No, as he said, if journalists are and root and pee in things-
-And asks if such people don't want to answer.
Then journalists are also people with faults and shortcomings.
But then it is important that the corrections are highlighted and so on.
Now it turns out that he found most things.
He has mostly worked for Der Spiegel, but has also been published abroad.
And almost all his reports are fictional.
So embarrassing!
He has worked at huge story-
-And had started to fake things and find details.
Some colleagues had no idea and tried to warn the managers ...
-. but they didn't listen.
-It became a splendor scandal.
They would have listened.
The magazine had to do about a lot, they had to check all he wrote-